Finding Aid for the Los Angeles Unified School District Board of Education Records LSC.1923
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Publications, 1884-2009
  - Who's Who Registers, 1972-1980
    Bound lists of notable alumni organized alphabetically by area and school name. Materials also include captions, graduation years, achievements, photos and criteria for selection. Alumni areas of professional activity include sports, drama, government, business, military, education, medicine, law, science and clergy. Notable alumni include Frank Capra, Edith Head, Derrell Thomas, Augustus F. Hawkins, Makoto Sakamoto, Johnnie L. Cochran Jr., Norman Chandler, Yvonne Braithwaite Burke, Carol Burnett, Warren Christopher, Richard Alatorre, Edward R. Roybal, Benjamin Earl Davidson, Clarence Charles Merriman, Oscar L. Gallego, Daryl Gates, Tom Bradley, the Smothers Brothers, Gin Wong, Sally Field, Robert Redford, Don Drysdale, Samuel Cernuto, Willie Crawford, Maralin Miska and Sammy Lee.
    - Alumni Who's Who, 1972-1980 (Box 2636)
  - School Registers, 1968-1993
    The School Registry 1855-1968 is the second edition of the Chronology first published in 1963. This book contains alphabetical lists of schools organized by the following section divisions: Elementary Schools, Junior High Schools, Senior High Schools, Special Education Schools, Adult Schools and Junior Colleges. Records include date named, former name and date named, date opened, comments and date closed. Materials also include the third and fourth editions of the Chronology entitled, History of Schools Chronology, a list of currently operating schools which includes opening or annexation dates and three Names of Schools binders which are organized alphabetically by school name and include opening dates, name and name change dates, closure dates, principal names and dates of standing committee reports authorizing names, openings, annexations and name changes. Additional copies of History of Schools Chronology may be found in either the Schools or Schools - History subject files.
    - School Registry 1855-1968, 1968 September (Box 2637, Folder 1)
    - History of Schools Chronology 1855-1972, 1973 January (Box 2637, Folder 2)
    - History of Schools (Chronology) 1855-1993, 1993 October (Box 2637, Folder 3)
    - Los Angeles Bicentennial Origins of School Names, 1981 (Box 2637, Folder 4)
    - Currently Operating Schools - Opening or Annexation - By Year, 1975 February 25 (Box 2637, Folder 5)
    - Names of Schools, undated (Box 2637, Folder 6-8)
  - Directories, 1888-1982
    Booklets contain school names, addresses, lists of board members and employee phone numbers, addresses and positions.
    - Handbooks of Los Angeles City Schools, 1895-1897 (Box 2638)
    - Directories of Los Angeles City Schools, 1898-1908 (Box 2638)
    - Directories of the Los Angeles City Elementary and High School Districts, 1910-1924 (Box 2638)
    - Directories of the Los Angeles City Elementary and High School Districts, 1924-1929 (Box 2639)
    - Directories of the Los Angeles City Elementary and High School Districts, 1888-1925, 1929-1931 (Box 2640)
      Materials include individual and bound directories.
    - Directories of the Los Angeles City Elementary and High School Districts, 1928-1947 (Box 2641)
      Bound directories.
    - Directories of the Los Angeles City Elementary, High School and Junior College Districts, 1931-1937 (Box 2642)
    - Teachers' Directories, 1902-1918 (Box 2642)
    - Teachers' Directories, 1918-1927 (Box 2643)
    - Teachers' Directories, 1926-1933 (Box 2644)
    - Teachers' Directories, 1909-1935 (Box 2645)
      Materials include red bound directories.
    - Teachers' Directories, 1920-1936 (Box 2646)
      Copies belonging to Superintendent Susan M. Dorsey and Superintendent Frank A. Bouelle.
    - Directories of the Personnel, 1936-1941 (Box 2647)
    - Directories of the Personnel, 1946-1950 (Box 2648)
    - Personnel Directories, 1936-1940 (Box 2648)
      Copies compiled and bound.
    - Personnel Directories, 1936-1950 (Box 2649)
      Copies are compiled and bound.
    - Personnel Directories, 1946-1950 (Box 2650)
    - Telephone Directories, 1972-1982 (Box 2650)
    - Los Angeles County Public Schools Directories, 1912-1974 (Box 2651)
  - Guides, 1918-2005
    Booklets contain alphabetical lists of schools, addresses, maps, phone numbers and principals. The earliest version of these guides was called Alphabetical List of Schools but its name changed to Guide to Schools and Offices in 1949.
    - Alphabetical Lists of Schools, 1918-1948 (Box 2652)
    - Guides to Schools and Offices, 1949-1959 (Box 2652)
    - Guides to Schools and Offices, 1959-1983 (Box 2653)
    - Guides to Schools and Offices, 1985-1997 (Box 2654)
    - Guides to Schools and Offices, 1996-2000 (Box 2655)
    - Guides to Schools and Offices, 1999-2001 (Box 2656)
    - Guides to Schools and Offices, 2002-2005 (Box 2657)
  - Financial Booklets, 1947-1979
    Booklets contain financial and statistical data concerning personnel such as salary schedules, salary ratings, proposed expenditures and actual expenditures.
    - Financial and Statistical Data, 1947-1972 (Box 2658)
    - Personnel Data, 1970-1972 (Box 2658)
    - Statistical Financial Personnel Data, 1972-1979 (Box 2658)
  - Reports, Surveys and Studies, 1916-1971
    These research reports, surveys and studies were authorized by the Board and executed by independent agencies.
    - Report on Organization and Administration of the Public School System, 1916 April 17-1916 May 22 (Box 2658)
    - Survey of the Los Angeles City Schools, 1934 (Box 2658)
      Two copies.
    - Reports Upon Examinations of the Los Angeles City School Districts, 1951 June 30 (Box 2659)
    - Report to the Board of Education, 1962 December 17 (Box 2659)
    - Los Angeles City Unified School District Study of the Maintenance Branch Phase I, 1971 June 17 (Box 2659)
  - Yearbooks, 1915-1976
    Junior and senior high school yearbooks.
    - The Poinsettia, 1915-1917, 1919-1920 (Box 2660, Folder 1-3)
      Hollywood High School.
    - The Artisan, 1926-1930 (Box 2661, Folder 1, Box 2660, Folder 4-6)
      Manual Arts High School.
    - The A9 Idea, 1933-1934 (Box 2661, Folder 2)
      Central Junior High School.
    - The Year, 1972, 1974 (Box 2662, Folder 1, Box 2661, Folder 3-4)
      John F. Kennedy High School. Box 2,661: Two copies of the 1972 yearbook. Box 2,662: One copy of the 1974 yearbook.
    - The Scroll, 1973-1974 (Box 2661, Folder 5)
      James Madison Junior High School.
    - The Torch, 1974-1975 (Box 2662, Folder 2, Box 2661, Folder 6)
      Joaquin Miller High School
    - Las Palmas, 1974-1975 (Box 2662, Folder 3, Box 2661, Folder 7)
      Palms Junior High School.
    - Gompers Artisan, 1974-1975 (Box 2661, Folder 8, Box 2662, Folder 6)
      Samuel Gompers Junior High.
    - The El Arador, 1975-1976 (Box 2662, Folder 4 and 7)
      Gardena High School.
    - Area F Alternative School, 1975 (Box 2662, Folder 5)
  - Theses and Books, 1928-2007
    The bulk of these materials consist of theses created by academics who utilized the subject files and Board Reports that were maintained by the Board Secretariat's File Unit.
    - Genesis of the Los Angeles Board of Education and City Superintendent of Schools, undated (Box 2663, Folder 1)
      By Sherman H. Freeman.
    - A Study of the Development of Elementary Education in Los Angeles City, 1928 March 24 (Box 2663, Folder 2)
      By Elizabeth Bates.
    - The History of Secondary Education in the City of Los Angeles, 1940 February (Box 2663, Folder 3)
      By Harry Sargent.
    - The Rise and Expansion of Public Secondary Education in the Los Angeles City High School District, 1940 (Box 2663, Folder 4)
      By Mary Grace Jensen.
    - Industrial Arts in the Los Angeles City Schools Prior to 1900, 1955 August (Box 2663, Folder 5)
      By Marion Avakian.
    - An Historical Analysis of the Black Administrator in the Los Angeles Unified School District, 1972 (Box 2664, Folder 1)
      By Don J. Wilson.
    - From Discipline to Punishment: Race, Bureaucracy, and School Discipline Policy in Los Angeles, 1954-1975, 2004 June 1 (Box 2664, Folder 2)
      By Judith Rachel Kafka.
    - Fighting Fire with Fire: The Los Angeles School Desegregation Battle, 2004 April 6 (Box 2664, Folder 3)
      By Rachel Deborah Bernard.
    - The Red Lacquer Bridge, 2007 (Box 2664, Folder 4)
      By Maggie Shelton
  - Bulletins, 1917-1924
    - The Bulletin of the Los Angeles City Teachers Club, 1917-1924 (Box 2665)
      Nine bulletins published monthly as a means of communication between the Board of Directors and the Members.
  - Programs, 1914-1934
    - California Teachers' Association, 1914-1934 (Box 2665)
      Convention programs for the Institute of the City of Los Angeles and the Institute of the County of Los Angeles.
  - State Reports, 1904-1960
    Materials published by the California Department of Education.
    - Biennial Report of the Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1904 (Box 2665, Folder unknown container)
    - California Biennial School Report, 1913 (Box 2665)
    - California State Board of Education Life Diploma, 1920 (Box 2665)
    - School Law of California, 1921 (Box 2665)
    - Report of the California Commission for the Study of Educational Problems, 1930 (Box 2665)
      This copy was Superintendent Susan M. Dorsey's who served as the chairman of this commission.
    - Directory of California Superintendents of Schools, 1944 October (Box 2665)
      This directory was published as a bulletin of the California State Department of Education.
    - Enrollment in California Public Schools Reports, 1947 October 31-1960 March 31 (Box 2665)